hey everybody welcome to this b1 english
listening practice video
you can use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension
as i speak before we start remember to
subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram you ready
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about
adulthood this is a topic that many of
you can relate to
because i assume that the majority of my
viewers are adults
some of us wish we were still kids
sometimes but there's nothing we can do
to roll back the time
so first let's talk about some of the
most notable differences that exist
between childhood and adulthood the
first thing that comes to mind is the
responsibility that comes with being an
adult
this is something that most kids and
teenagers underestimate about adulthood
for example when i was in high school i
couldn't wait to be an adult
i thought the responsibilities wouldn't
be as hard as everyone always told me
they'd be
but boy was i wrong young people simply
can't imagine
all the challenges that adulthood
presents of course they know that
they'll probably get married move out of
their parents house and of course have a
career
and make enough money to support a
family it sounds relatively
straightforward but it's definitely
harder than we think it is when we're
still young
it was a challenge for me to become
independent from my parents
because they'd always paid for
everything and helped me with all my
problems
when you take that security away it's a
little scary for a young adult
becoming financially independent is
undoubtedly one of the hardest things
about being an adult
for example those of you who pay rent
know that it can sometimes be a struggle
especially if you're still in an early
stage of your career
i think that parents should spend a lot
of time teaching their kids about
financial responsibility
this way when they're adults they won't
have to learn everything from scratch
they'll already have a good foundation
to build upon how about you
was it hard for you to become
financially independent
aside from the financial aspect the
other huge responsibility
is getting married and raising children
choosing the right husband or wife
is one of the most critical decisions
we'll ever make
if you choose wrong you're going to have
to live with the consequences of that
for the rest of your
life however even if you choose the
right spouse you're still going to face
all kinds of challenges in your marriage
that's a given
it's our responsibility to work with our
spouse as a team
to overcome these challenges those of
you who are married know exactly what
i'm talking about
and of course everything gets a little
more complicated when we have kids
at that point you take on much more
responsibility
okay now let's talk about some of the
positives of being an adult
for me one of the best things is being
able to make decisions for myself
when you're an adult you get to decide
your own future
you can choose the path you want to take
this isn't easy
but i think it's exciting you get to
pick your career your spouse your
residents
etc etc another great thing about being
an adult
is that you understand the world better
when you're a child
you still have a limited view of the
world around you and you have limited
experience but as an adult you're able
to see things more clearly
in turn this means that you solve
problems more effectively
and learn from your mistakes more easily
one last
positive about being an adult is that
you can accomplish more
with the exception of child prodigies
people in general
achieve the most when they're fully
grown as an adult
you've probably already studied and
gained experience
so you're more prepared to do
significant things with your life
i hope i can achieve a lot in my adult
life and i'll definitely continue
setting goals for myself to make sure i
do that okay
now i'm gonna ask you three questions
about today's video to check your
comprehension
write your answers in a comment down
below number one
what's one challenge of being an adult
number two
what's one positive thing about being an
adult and number three
what will i do to make sure i achieve a
lot in my adult life
alright before we go remember to
subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram for more english tips and
lessons
i'll see you next time
[Music]